Guide to the Stanford University, Program in Human Biology, Honors Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Theses, Accession ARCH-1993-058
  - Godinho, Christina, Contraception and Orthodox Judaism: The Application of Religious Guidelines to Contraceptive Technology., June, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Klugman, Craig M., The Social Transmission of the Incest Taboo in American Culture., May, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Han Ne, The Expression of Gonadotropin-Releasing Hormone Neurons During Early Development in Haplochromis burtoni., June, 1992 (Box 2)
  - McJennett, Patricia, What in the Wild? An Evaluation of Visitor Learning in the Wildlife Habitats Exhibit at Cooyote Point Museum., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Pan, Erica, Correlates and Barriers to Breastfeeding Initiation among Disadvantaged Mothers., June 1992 (Box 2)
  - Peng, Amy, Rhythm of Retinal Cell Divisions in Haplochromis burtoni., September 1992 (Box 2)
  - Pereira, Sharlene C., The Selection and Characterization of Internal Anti-Idiotype Antibodies for Human Cytomegalovirus Glycoprotein B., June 1992 (Box 2)
  - Soma, Kiran, The Effects of Sex Hormones on Aggressive Behavior and Gonadotropin-Releasing Hormone (GnRH) Neurons in the Male Teleost Fish "Haplochromis burtoni"., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Stroud, Laura, The Effects of Ruminative and Distracting Responses to Depression on Predictions of Utility and Likelihood of Engaging in Distracting Activities., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Taneja, Gayatri, A Study of Social Interactions: Attitudes and Perceptions of People with Disabilities., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Vernon, Dan, Adaptive Plasticity of the Linear Vestibulo-Ocular Reflex., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Williams, Joy, Patients' Perceptions and Access to Eye Care in Jamaica., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Wolfe, Nathan, Smoking Status and Health-Related Attitudes and Behaviors Among Undergraduates in England and U.S.A., 1992 (Box 2)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-1993-126
  - Arboleda, Mary Jo, RecA Protein-Mediated Homologous DNA Targeting in Metabolically Active Human Nuclei as Monitored by Fluorescent InSitu Hybridization., June, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Balt, Steve, Egr-1 Activation and Clucocorticoid Modulation of the Rat PNMT Gene., August 1993 (Box 1)
  - Bramlage, Cathy, Analysis of the Endangered Species Act and Its Impending Reauthorization., May, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Carlsten, Chris, Water Disinfection By-Product Regulatory Negotiations: Resolving Uncertainites of Risk., May, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Chow, Howard, Investigation into the Presence of Multi-xenobiotic Resistance in the Tunicate, Ciona intestinalis., June, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Chu, Kathryn, An In Vitro Model for the Study of Human chorioamniotic Membrances: Permeability Characteristics and Glucose Utlization., May, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Chung, Angela, Childhood Lead Poisoning in Asian-American Populations: Current Research and Future Recommendations., 1993 (Box 1)
  - Cornwall, Roger, Interaction of Synthetic Organic Pollutants with the Multixenobiotic Resistance Mechanism in the Marine Mussel, Mytilus californianus., May, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Espeut, Donna, English Learning Babies Prefer Infant Directed Speech, Even in Japanese., June, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Goodman, Karyn, Combating Non-insulin Dependent Diabetes Mellitus in the Native American Community: A Culturally-Relevant Diabetes Intervention Program., May, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Gutierrez, Kristina, The Health Status of Mexican American Women in the United States: The Prevalence of Chronic Medical Conditions., May, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Halaas, Michael, Fetal Suprachiasmatic Tranplantation Into Partially functioning Circadian Timekeeping Systems., 1993 (Box 2)
  - Hamilton, Joanne, Can College Students Exhibit Characteristics of Alzheimer's Disease? An Investigation of the Effects of Divided Attention on Semantic Priming., May, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Hua, Tina, The Study of Multicultural Implementation in a Large Organization, Specifically Stanford University., May 1993 (Box 2)
  - Iyangar, Vikram, Nectar Foraging Strategies in Heliconius Charitonius., May, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Knepper, Kate, The Histoy of American Women in Radiation Therapy., May, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Kostishack, Amy, A Study of the Social, Cultural and Psychlogical Factors That Contribute to Psychosomatic Vision Loss in Hmong and Cambodian Women in Minneapolis and St. Paul, Minnesota., June, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Lam, Prudence, Speech Content Analysis of Children with Cancer and Diabetes., May, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Lee, Stephen, A Study of the Circadian Rhythmicity of Vasopressin Levels in Cultured and Slice Preparations of the Suprachiasmatic Nucleus., 1993 (Box 2)
  - Lehrer, Kathy, Effects of Histamine Congener Drugs on the Rat Allogenic Immune Response., May 1993 (Box 2)
  - Lu, Flora, Changing Perceptions of the Relationship Between Indigenous people and the Environment: A Case Study of the Waorani of the Ecuadorian Amazon., May 1993 (Box 3)
  - Marie, Ariane, Division of Attention as a Model For Cognitive and Emotional Disorders in Schizophrenia., May, 1993 (Box 3)
  - McGowan, Anne, Correlations Between the Quality of Women's Intimate Sexual Relationships and the Quality of Their Physical Health., May 1993 (Box 3)
  - Misakian, Stacy, Women's Knowledge of Female Hormones After Menopause: A Survery of Stanford Women Alumni., May 1993 (Box 3)
  - Norman, Bridget, A Study of the Functional Aspects of T-Cell Receptor Superantigen Interactions: The Roles of CDRS 1 and 2, and the "DE" Loop., May 1993 (Box 3)
  - Novy, Julia, Women, Work and Empowerment in Rural Zanzibar: A Case Study in Nungwi and Paje Villages., 1993 (Box 3)
  - Powell, Valerie, A Comparison of Cultured and Natural Red Abalone (Haliotis rufenscens) Populations Leading to a Reevaluation of the California Abalone Enhancement Programs., May 1993 (Box 3)
  - Scull, Grant, Human Fertility in El Salvador; A Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis of The Salvadoran Fertility Determinants., 1993 (Box 3)
  - Shenkel, Jill, Learning It, Living It, and Liking It: A Look at Elementary Science Education., 1993 (Box 3)
  - Shepard, Thomas, Implementation Assessment of Current Effectiveness Proposed Modification Increased Funding., 1993 (Box 3)
  - Tong, Garrison, The Role of the Dorsal Raphe Nucleus in Arousal State Control and Sensory Information Processing., 1993 (Box 3)
  - Tsai, Conyee L., Practice and Other Determinants of Laparoscopic Skill Acquisition and Performance., 1993 (Box 3)
  - Uddin, Monica, Coming of Age in an Era of AIDS: The Effects on College Women's Sexuality., 1993 (Box 3)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Heberling, Lindsay, The medical beliefs and practices of the Chamacoco: Karcha Bahlut, Paraguay., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Elizabeth H., Textualizing science: investigating narrative discord between the humanities and sciences., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Lin, Cindy Yuchin, Effect of equine facilitated therapy on the gait and standing balance of children with cerebral palsy., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Lloyd, Stephanie, Genetic self selection: the behavioral and attitudinal effects of Apoliproprotein A-1 Milano., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Long, Bria L., The role of languages in eye-witness memory: remembering who did it in English and Japanese., 2009 (Box 1)
  - Nguyen, Elizabeth K., Who runs the household? A comparison study of the effects of acculturation on gender role attitudes and practices in Vietnamese and Vietnamese American households., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Old, Matthew O., Development of chemiluminescent probe hybridization, RT-PCR and nucleic acid cycle sequencing assays of Sabin type 3 isolates to identify base pair 472 Sabin type 3 mutants associated with vaccine-associated paralytic poliomyelitis., undated [1997] (Box 1)
  - Phillips, Erica M., Hohokam mortuary practices at the classic period site of Escalante ruin., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Renfro, Sarna, Assessing the nutritional effects of the Food Stamp and WIC programs on the diets of women and children., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Wells, Sarah "Katie", The effect of genetic counseling on women's perceptions of fetal risk after receiving a positive expanded AFP result: questionnaire trends and four case studies., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Yock, Cynthia, Cost-effectiveness modeling of coronary interventions., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Yun, Irene, The role of Cortisol in regulating social behavior and GnRH releasing neuronal soma size in Haplochromis burtoni., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Au, Teresa, Social regulation of gonadotropin-releasing hormone receptor in the cichlid fish, Haplochromis burtoni., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Barnett, Katie, The time perspective of the New Zealand Maori., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Bryan-Jones, Katherine, College students' sexual risk taking: the impact of cognitive time perspective, sex education background, and psycho-social attitudes., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Carlson, Erin R., The integrated index of ecosystem health: development and application to six protected zones in Costa Rica., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Chao, Elaine, Pushing for social change: the domestic violence movement in Taiwan., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Cheng, Jonathan, Changes in respiratory muscle performance at high altitude with acclimatization and caloric restriction., 2001 (Box 2)
  - Cisco, Michael J., Reported repeats within intron 23 of human elastin show little length polymorphism; an RFLP found within the deletion associated with Williams syndrome (WS); a newly discovered gene within the WS deletion appears rarely expressed., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Dorth, Jenny, Cloning of the rearranged Vα3.5 and Vß6 T-cell receptor and ligation into a TCR Transgene expression vector., 2001 (Box 2)
  - Hsieh, Valerie S., How stratified classrooms and school systems influence the formation of concepts of ability in German and American schoolchildren., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Kerns, Kara Lynn, Cloning and expression of Glycoprotein G of Herpes Simplex Virus Type 2 in a mammalian cell line., 1990 (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Charmian, Universal HIV screening of pregnant women in California: a cost-effectiveness analysis., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Lin, Leo, The molecular pathways by which ethanol and PKC peptide modulators provide cardioprotection., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Taylor, Tatiana L., Adolescent males and body image: the relationship between masculinity and muscularity., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Wright, Alexi, Women on the edge: single women homesteaders in nineteenth-century Nebraska., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Tongson, Sebastian Eclevia Jr., Factors affecting the geographical and demographical distribution of patterns of Bancroftian lymphatic filariasis in Sorsogon, Philippines., undated (Box 2)
  - Ahmad, Iman, Preventing childhood diarrhea in Pakistan: maternal beliefs, practices and socio-economic constraints., 2005 (Box 3)
  - Bernstein, Aaron, Exploring associations between depression and immunity in spouses of advanced breast cancer patients., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Doty, Nathan Daniel, The impact of social identity cues on eye movement during face perception., undated (Box 3)
  - Eng, Lillian, Increasing access to health care for Cambodian refugees for the year 2000., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Amber, Egg donor recruitment at Stanford: assessing and reducing ethical conflicts., 2001 (Box 3)
  - Knaebel, Sergio, What motivates the "ecological peasant?": a local perspective on conservation in the El Triunfo Biosphere Reserve, Chiapas., 1992 (Box 3)
  - Minta, Anna, Malaria beliefs and behaviors in the Asanta region of Ghana., 2003 (Box 3)
  - Murakami, Yohko, Children's sensitivity to the expertise of the speaker when learning new words: a cross-cultural study., 2004 (Box 3)
  - Murcia, Maria, Revealing the views of MD/MBA candidates: attitudes and expectations of their training and beyond., 2006 (Box 3)
  - Pogue, Zachary, Telemedicine: a look at the history and future prospects of a disruptive technology., 2003 (Box 3)
  - Widman, Allison, The cost-effectiveness of dose-dense versus conventionally scheduled combination chemotherapy as postoperative adjuvant treatment for node-positive primary breast cancer., 2003 (Box 3)
  - Wojtkowski, Dorothy, Women at high altitude (4300m): basal metabolic rate and thyroid hormones., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Wood, Margaret H., A prospective study of characteristics which predict pregnancy involvement in adolescents., 1996 (Box 3)
  - Wu, Charlotte A., Chronic Hepatitis B and liver cancer knowledge and preventive action in the high risk Chinese American community., 2001 (Box 3)
  - Basu, Sreyashi Jhumki, The heatlh of street children in Moscow and St. Petersburg., 1998 (Box 4)
  - Boyce, Ebony A., Access to bone marrow transplants for multiple myeloma patients: the role of race., 2000 (Box 4)
  - Ehrenreich, Ian Michael, The ecology and evolution of triclosan-resistant Escherichia coli., undated [2001?] (Box 4)
  - Farghalli, Nancy, Non timber forest product certification: a case study of palm in Chilapa, Mexico., 1997 (Box 4)
  - Gestrin, Emily D., A second form of gonadotropin-releasing hormone in mouse., 1998 (Box 4)
  - Gurney, Theresa A., Development of a retroviral packaging vector to characterize HIV-1 transcriptional regulation., 1997 (Box 4)
  - Henderson, Shanta P., The myth of the "crack baby"?., 1996 (Box 4)
  - Horton, Lucy, Adherence to antiretroviral therapy in Uganda: a case study of Reach Out, Kampala, Uganda., 2005 (Box 4)
  - Jolley, Jennifer A., Development of a broad-range fungal 18S rDNA PCR assay for use in determining the phylogeny of Rhinosporidium seeberi, a human pathogen., 1998 (Box 4)
  - King, Josephine, Brain activiation patterns in daughters of depressed and nondepressed mothers., 2001 (Box 4)
  - Kolhatkar, Gauri, The complexity of reproductive health education in India: attitudes toward and levels of education among a survey of women in Pune, Maharashtra., 1999 (Box 4)
  - Lee, Richard Y., The acculturation and self-identificaiton of Asian Americans: a study of seven ethnic groups., undated (Box 4)
  - Ng, Rita K. and Phillina A. Lai, A never-ending story: the effects of perceived time and age on cultural differences in social preferences., 2000 (Box 4)
  - Nguyen, Rita, Comparing food content and preference in areas of varying socioeconomic status in Santa Clara County., 2005 (Box 4)
  - Parikh, Victoria Nicole, Stress, hormones and reproduction in the African Cichlid fish, Astatotilapia burtoni., 2005 (Box 4)
  - Sugino, Julie, The effects of health care reform on clinical medical ethics., 1996 (Box 4)
  - Woo, Stacey Mayhene, Transgenesis in sea urchin embryos by sperm-mediated gene transfer., 2001 (Box 4)
  - Blumling, Mark, The colonization of the Brazilian Amazon: an eclectic examination and projection of pathogens, settlement strategies and health policies following the decade of destruction., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Cohen, Jennifer, Teenage cigarette smoking initiation: smoking trends and attitudes among Italian high school students., 1999 (Box 5)
  - Green, Ronald J., Working and reference memory processes., 1985 (Box 5)
  - Kimmel, Bonnie, The schooling of Thai Karen girls: women at the edge of the village., 1995 (Box 5)
  - Magnani, Kalee Geiderman, Are developmental changes in the speed and accuracy of word recognition related to vocabulary growth in the second year?., 1999 (Box 5)
  - Maynard, Jennifer Anne and Jenny Eileen Scheuerlein, Comparison of induced abortion and contraceptive method choice among urban American and Japanese university students., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Reyes, Abigail S., Digging for meaning: environment, community, and work at the Garden Project., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Sohoni, Aparajita, Addressing the physiological and social implications of leprosy: a case-study analysis of an NGO's method for holistic patient rehabilitation., 1999 (Box 5)
  - Steenland, Alice, Drug testing in high schools: an examination of the balancing test in Fourth Amendment cases., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Tucker, Jennifer, Bees, corks, monsters, and mites: the scientific debut of the compound microscope and retooling of discovery in Seventeenth Century England., 1988 (Box 5)
  - Nudleman, Eric and Dale Kaiser, Assembly of polar type IV pili in Myxococcus xanthus., 2000 (Box 6)
  - Lee, Sulggi A., The effects of fine particulate matter air contamination (PM 2.5) on lower acute respiratory infections in Santiago, Chile., 1998 (Box 6)
  - Maldonado, Janet L., A small battle won in the war against autoimmunity; PKA antagonizes calcineurin induced nuclear translocation of NF-ATp., 1998 (Box 6)
  - Tsai, Vivian, Downregulation of BCL-2 using antisense oligodeoxynucleotides sensitizes human uterine sarcoma cells to Paclitaxel (Taxol®)., 1999 (Box 6)
  - Rhee, Michelle Sang Min, Use of cellular markers, CD4 lymphocyte counts and CD4/CD8 ratios,combined with early clinical symptoms to predict human immunodeficiency virus infection in individuals from Harare, Zimbabwe., 1995 (Box 6)
  - Yang, Elise W., Performance anxiety in individually performing collegiate athletes and musicians., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Lorenz, Katie, The conservation of global biodiversity: a comparison of US and German perspectives., 2000 (Box 6)
  - Lipton, Shira, Comparison of direct-to-customer prescription drug advertising on Hispanic versus mainstream broadcast media., 2001 (Box 6)
  - Perry, Caroline, Emotional expression during narratives in a breast cancer support group., 2001 (Box 6)
  - Lehman, Jessica, Disabled people's perceptions of their community., 2000 (Box 6)
  - Yee, Lynn Meredith, Biracial Asian American adolescents: sexual decision-making and communication., 2003 (Box 6)
  - Bischoff, Kara, Asx maintains anterior-posterior fate in the Drosophila wing through regulation of Ubx., 2004 (Box 6)
  - Kao, Mimi H. F., Social status and stress hormones in Haplochromis burtoni., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Rice, Elizabeth, Nitrate, development and trade liberalization: a case study of the Yaqui Valley, Mexico., 1995 (Box 6)
  - Parker, Emily Lyle, Environmental interest and concern among eighth grade students: common perspectives and regional differences., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Hegde, Sheela, Patients who use yoga based therapy for chronic disease in Bangalore, India: factors associated with the choice of complementary care in India's medical pluralism., 2000 (Box 7)
  - Ahasic, Heather M., The accuracy and effectiveness of television health and medical news: a pilot study., 1999 (Box 7)
  - Marks, Heather, Policy for permanence: national park recreation and the future of McCarthy, Alaska., 1993 (Box 7)
  - Liu, Catherine, Determinants of infant and child mortality in Sierra Leone: strategies for policy intervention., 1997 (Box 7)
  - Jain, Seema, Educational approaches to the knowledge and attitudes about HIV and AIDS of Bombay college students., 1994 (Box 7)
  - Lee, Jay W., Initiation of growth in somites by neural tube during vertebrate myogenesis., 1995 (Box 7)
  - Milam, Susan, Sex diagnosis and selection in California: a survey of genetic counselors., 1995 (Box 7)
  - Walsh, Allison Chapman, From complacency to panic: American attitude change regarding infectious disease from the 1950s to the 1990s., 1995 (Box 7)
  - Kroonen, Leo T., Biculturalism and self-esteem: social context as a determinant for self-perception., 1995 (Box 7)
  - Goldman, Lisa Beth, The application of protected area user fees to local development initiatives: a case study of Costa Rica., 1994 (Box 7)
  - Kikuchi, Julie Sumie, "The tuberculosis problem": a quiet legacy of the Japanese-American internment camps., 1995 (Box 7)
  - Thompson, Darcy, Chronically ill children: health care reform and the role of public health., 1994 (Box 7)
  - Merrill, Deborah E., Life is health is life': understanding and improving baseline Aboriginal health status., 1997 (Box 8)
  - Chang, Jeannie Y., Epidemiology of herpes simplex virus type 2 (HSV-2) infections among juvenile detention hall clinic attendees., 1996 (Box 8)
  - Chao, Jing-Chyi, The effects of math identity and gender on expectations and performance in math., 1998 (Box 8)
  - Chen, Christine Y., Overcoming the barriers to timely childhood immunization., 1998 (Box 8)
  - Dandekar, Ajai A., Signaling abilities of the cytoplasmic domain of the insulin receptor-related receptor., 1998 (Box 8)
  - Kim, Yoona, Downstream targets of let-60 Ras in C. elegans., 2002 (Box 8)
  - Fong, Suzy, Cultural competency of health care delivery towards Latino patients in the Bay Area., 2002 (Box 8)
  - Penner, Kristine, The dilemma of Latino immigrants: health access and health seeking behaviors in a changing political climate., 1998 (Box 8)
  - Dilawari, Asma, Characteristics of family planning in Pakistan: women's perspective., 1996 (Box 8)
  - Magarian, Luisa, Portraits of change: women's lives over 58 years in a Mayan town; San Pedro, La Laguna, Guatemala., 2001 (Box 8)
  - Ahmad, Iman, Preventing childhood diarrhea in Pakistan: maternal beliefs, practices and socio-economic constraints., 2005
  - Au, Teresa, Social regulation of gonadotropin-releasing hormone receptor in the cichlid fish, Haplochromis burtoni., 2003